{
  "translations": {
    "en": {
      "fa1": "../../../AV/VisFormalLang/NFA/AutomataFiles/NFA2DFA2a.jff",
      "q1": {
        "type": "select",
        "src": "../../../AV/Development/formal_language/FAEditor.html",
        "description": "Start with the alphabet set. We normally represent an alphabet set with $\\Sigma$. The alphabet set is a set of symbols (typically letters or characters, but it could include any symbols}.",
        "question": "Which of the following are  alphabet sets?",
        "answer": ["$\\{a, b, c\\}$", "$\\{0, 1\\}$", "$\\{?, a, x\\}$"],
        "choices": ["$\\{a, b, c\\}$", "$\\{0, 1\\}$", "$A$", "$\\{?, a, x\\}$"]
      },
      "q111":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "question": "[T/F] c) $A$ is not the answer because it is just a character",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": ["True", "False"]
      },
      "q2": {
        "type": "select",
        "src": "../../../AV/Development/formal_language/FAEditor.html",
        "description": "Given some alphabet set $\\Sigma$, a string is a finite sequence of symbols (taken from $\\Sigma$, of course). Suppose we have $\\Sigma = \\{a, b\\}$, which of the following are valid strings?",
        "question": "Suppose we have $\\Sigma$ = $\\{a, b\\}$, which of the following are valid strings?",
        "answer": ["$babababbaba$", "$a$"],
        "choices": ["$babababbaba$", "$a$", "$\\{aaa, bbb\\}$", "$bacbabcba$"]
      },
      "q2_2": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Given some alphabet set $\\Sigma$, a string is a finite sequence of symbols (taken from $\\Sigma$, of course). Suppose we have $\\Sigma = \\{a, b\\}$",
        "question": "Does $\\{aaa, bbb\\}$ a valid string?",
        "answer": "No, because $\\{aaa, bbb\\}$ is a set",
        "choices": ["Yes, it is a valid string", "No, because $\\{aaa, bbb\\}$ is a set"]
      },
      "q2_3": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Given some alphabet set $\\Sigma$, a string is a finite sequence of symbols (taken from $\\Sigma$, of course). Suppose we have $\\Sigma = \\{a, b\\}$",
        "question": "[T/F] The choice $bacbabcba$ is not a vaild string in $\\Sigma$",
        "answer": "It is not a valid string as it includes letter not in $\\Sigma$",
        "choices": ["It is a valid sting", "It is not a valid string as it includes letter not in $\\Sigma$"]
      },
      "q3": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "A $\\textit{language}$ is simply a collection of strings defined over $\\Sigma$.",
        "question": "Which of the following are correct languages over their $\\Sigma$?",
        "answer": [
          "$\\Sigma$={$0,1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8, 9\\}$ $L=\\{0,1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,12,13,14,15,...\\}$",
          "$\\Sigma$={$a,b,c\\}$ $L=\\{ab,ac,cabb\\}$",
          "$\\Sigma$={$0,1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8, 9\\}$ $L=\\{set\\ of\\ all\\ even\\ numbers\\}$"
        ],
        "choices": [
          "$\\Sigma$={$0,1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8, 9\\}$ $L=\\{0,1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,12,13,14,15,...\\}$",
          "$\\Sigma$={$a,b,c\\}$ $L=\\{ab,ac,cabb\\}$",
          "$\\Sigma$={$0,1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8, 9\\}$ $L=\\{set\\ of\\ all\\ even\\ numbers\\}$"
        ]
      },
      "q3_2": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "A language is simply a collection of strings defined over $\\Sigma$.",
        "question": "Can $\\Sigma$=$\\{a,b,c\\}$ $L = ab$ be a language?",
        "answer": "No",
        "choices": ["Yes", "No"]
      },
      "q3_3": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "A language is simply a collection of strings defined over $\\Sigma$.",
        "question": "Can $\\Sigma$=$\\{a,b,c\\}$ $L = \\{a\\}$ be a language?",
        "answer": "Yes",
        "choices": ["Yes", "No"]
      },
      "q3_4": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "A language is simply a collection of strings defined over $\\Sigma$.",
        "question": "Can $\\Sigma$=$\\{a,b,c\\}$ $L$ = $\\{\\}$ be a language?",
        "answer": "Yes",
        "choices": ["Yes", "No"]
      },
      "q3_5": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Good, since a language is just a set of strings, the empty set is a perfectly good language.",
        "question": "Oh, and remember that we have a special symbol for “empty” set. Which is it?",
        "answer": "$\\{\\}$",
        "choices": ["$\\Sigma$", "$E$", "$\\{\\}$"]
      },
      "q4": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Another definition of a language is a subset of the powerset of $\\Sigma$. Remember from Discrete Math class that a power set of any set is the set of all possible subsets from the given set.",
        "question": "Choose what can be the power set of $\\{a, b\\}$",
        "answer": ["$\\{\\}$", "$\\{a\\}$", "$\\{b\\}$", "$\\{ab\\}$"],
        "choices": ["$\\{\\}$", "$\\{b\\}$", "$a$", "$\\{ab\\}$", "$b$","$\\{a\\}$", "$ab$"]
      },
      "q5": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Useful notations: We usually use these symbols in our book, For symbols in some alphabet $\\Sigma$, we typically use either digits or letters near the start of the common English alphabet: $a,b,c,d,0,1$ For string names (that is, some variable that is meant to refer to a string), we usually use letters near the end of the common English alphabet: $u,v,w,x,y,z$",
        "question": "So, when you see $b$ in a sentence, it probably refers to",
        "answer": "The character ‘$b$’.",
        "choices": ["The character ‘$b$’.", "Some string named ‘$b$’."]
      },
      "q5_1": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Useful notations: We usually use these symbols in our book, For symbols in some alphabet $\\Sigma$, we typically use either digits or letters near the start of the common English alphabet: $a,b,c,d,0,1$ For string names (that is, some variable that is meant to refer to a string), we usually use letters near the end of the common English alphabet: $u,v,w,x,y,z$",
        "question": "And if you see w in a sentence, it probably refers to ",
        "answer": "Some string given the name ‘$w$’",
        "choices": ["The character ‘$w$’", "Some string given the name ‘$w$’"]
      },
      "q6": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "There are some basic string operations we will use a lot. The size of a string is the number of symbols in the string.  We use the operator $|$$|$ to donate the size of the string.",
        "question": "Let $w=abbc$, $v=ab$, What is $|w|$ + $|v|$",
        "answer": "6",
        "choices": ["6", "7", "8"]
      },
      "q7": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Another important operation is string concatenation. The concatenation of two strings $u$, and v is just the string that contains the symbols of $u$ followed by the symbols of $v$. We use the symbol ∘ to represent concatenation: Example : Let $w$=$a1a2...an$, and $v$=$b1b2...bn$ Then, $w∘v$  = $a1a2...anb1b2...bm$",
        "question": "Let $w = abc$, $v = 012$, What is $w∘v$?",
        "answer": "$abc012$",
        "choices": ["$abc012$", "$012abc$", "$012$", "$abc$"]
      },
      "q7_1": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "In reality, we use concatenation so much that we hardly ever want to be that formal. When we mean w∘v, we will normally simply write $wv$ instead.",
        "question": "Let $w = abc$, $v = 012$, What is $wv$?",
        "answer": "$abc012$",
        "choices": ["$abc012$", "$012abc$", "$abc$", "$012$"]
      },
      "q8": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Another form of string concatenation is to concatenate a string with itself. Suppose we have a string $v$.  The notation $v^3$ means concatenate $v$ with itself 3 times. Concatenating a string with itself zero times yields the empty string $\\lambda$",
        "question": "let $v = ab$, what is $v^3$ ?",
        "answer": ["$vvv$", "$v∘v∘v$", "$ababab$"],
        "choices": ["$vvv$", "$v∘v∘v$", "$ababab$"]
      },
      "q8_1": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Recall, since a language is just a subset of all possible strings, that the empty set of strings is a language: $L$ = {} = &lt;empty set symbol&gt;.",
        "question": "Is this a language? $\\{\\lambda\\}$",
        "answer": "Yes",
        "choices": ["Yes", "No"]
      },
      "q9": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Concatenating any string with $\\lambda$  gives the same string. In other words, $\\lambda$ is the concatenation identity. For example, $ab$∘$\\lambda$=$\\lambda$∘$ab$=$ab$",
        "question": "What is $\\lambda∘acb∘\\lambda$?",
        "answer": "$acb$",
        "choices": ["$abc$","$acb$", "$bca$", "$bac$", "$cba$"]
      },
      "q10": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Another useful operation is to reverse a string: Reversing a string means to flip it, in other words, write its symbols in reverse order.",
        "question": "Let $w = abbc$, what is $w^R$? Note: R here means reverse",
        "answer": "$cbba$",
        "choices": ["$abbc$", "$bcab$", "$abcb$", "$cbab$","$cbba$"]
      },
      "q11": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Another useful operation is to reverse a string: Reversing a string means to flip it, in other words, write its symbols in reverse order.",
        "question": "let $w=abbc$, and $v=ab$. What is $|vv^Rw|$",
        "answer": "$8$",
        "choices": ["$8$", "$16$", "$24$", "$32$", "$40$"]
      },
      "q12": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "One of the most important operations that we use is the * operator, also called the closure operator. “*” of something means concatenating that something zero or more times. For example, if we have $\\Sigma$ = {a,b}, $\\Sigma$* means the set of strings obtained by concatenating 0 or more symbols from $\\Sigma$. ",
        "question": "Which of the following are strings in $\\Sigma^∗$?",
        "answer": ["$\\lambda$", "$a$", "$b$", "$aa$", "$abbabb$"],
        "choices": ["$\\lambda$", "$a$", "$b$", "$aa$", "$abbabb$", "$aaabababcc$"]
      },
      "q12_1": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "One of the most important operations that we use is the * operator, also called the closure operator. “*” of something means concatenating that something zero or more times. For example, if we have $\\Sigma$ = {a,b}, $\\Sigma$* means the set of strings obtained by concatenating 0 or more symbols from $\\Sigma$. ",
        "question": "Which are examples of $w^*$ where $w = abc$?",
        "answer": ["$\\lambda$", "$abc$", "$abcabc$"],
        "choices": ["$\\lambda$", "$aabbcc$", "$abc$", "$abcabc$"]
      },
      "q13": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Slightly different from the * operator, sometimes we want to have at least one copy of the thing that we are concatenating. Then we use +. One way of thinking of this: $\\Sigma$+=$\\Sigma$∗−{$\\lambda$}",
        "question": "Let  $\\Sigma = \\{a,b\\}$, Which of the following are strings in ?",
        "answer": ["$a$", "$b$", "$aa$", "$abbabb$"],
        "choices": [
          "$\\lambda$",
          "$a$",
          "$b$",
          "$aa$",
          "$abbabb$",
          "$aaabababcc$"
        ]
      },
      "q14": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Sets. As we see, Languages are sets, so all sets of operations can be applied to them.",
        "question": " Let $\\sigma$={$a$,$b$,$c$}, $L_1$={$ab$,$bc$,$aba$}, $L_2$={$c$,$bc$,$bcc$}, which element is included in $L_1∪L_2$ ?",
        "answer": ["ab" ,"bc","aba","c","bcc"],
        "choices": ["ab", "bc","a", "bca", "aba","c", "bcc","cb"]
      },
      "q15": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Sets. As we see, Languages are sets, so all sets of operations can be applied to them.",
        "question": "Let $\\Sigma=\\{a,b,c\\}$, $L_1=\\{ab,bc,aba\\}$, $L_2=\\{c,bc,bcc\\}$, what is $L_1∩L_2$ ?",
        "answer": "$bc$",
        "choices": ["$aba$", "$ab$", "$c$","$bc$", "$bcc$"]
      },
      "q16": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "In languages, $\\Sigma^*$  represents the Universe set $U$. For example, the complement of $L$ will be the set of all strings in $\\Sigma$ except the strings in $L$. In other words, $\\bar{L}$ = $\\Sigma^* - L$",
        "question": "Let $\\Sigma=\\{a,b,c\\}$, $L_1=\\{ab,bc,aba\\}$, $L_2=\\{c,bc,bcc\\}$, what is $\\overline{L_1∩L_2}$?",
        "answer": "$\\Sigma^* - \\{bc\\}$",
        "choices": ["$\\{bc\\}$", "$\\Sigma^* - \\{bc\\}$", " $\\Sigma^* \\cup \\{bc\\}$", "$\\Sigma - \\{bc\\}$"]
      },
      "q17": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Sets concatenation. Concatenating two sets $L1$, and $L2$ means concatenating every string in $L1$ with each string in $L2$.",
        "question": "Let $\\Sigma=\\{a,b,c\\}$, $L_1=\\{ab,bc,aba\\}$, $L_2=\\{c,bc,bcc\\}$, which of the following is $L_1L_2$?",
        "answer": "$\\{abc,abbc,abbcc,bcc,bcbc,bcbcc,abac,ababc,ababcc\\}$",
        "choices": [ "$\\{abc,abbc,abbcc,bcc,bcbc,bcbcc,abac,ababc,abab\\}$","$\\{abc,abbc,abbcc,bcc,bcbc,bcbcc,abac,ababc,ababcc\\}$", "$\\{abc,abbc,abbcc,bcc,bbcc,bcbcc,abac,abab,ababcc\\}$"]
      },
      "q18": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Sets concatenation. Concatenating a set zero times will give the set of the empty string $\\lambda$.",
        "question": "Let $\\Sigma$={$a$,$b$}, $L$={$ab$,$aba$}, What is $L^0$?",
        "answer": ["$\\{\\lambda\\}$"],
        "choices": ["$\\{\\lambda\\}$", "$\\{\\}$&lt;Empty set&gt;", "$\\lambda$"]
      },
      "q19": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Sets concatenation. Concatenating a set n times means concatenating every string in L with each string in $L$ n times",
        "question": "Let $\\Sigma$={$a$,$b$}, $L$={$ab$,$aba$}, What is $L^2$? ",
        "answer": "$\\{abab, ababa, abaab, abaaba\\}$",
        "choices": ["$\\{abab, ababa, abaab, abaaba\\}$", "$\\{ab, ababa, abaa, abaa\\}$", "$\\{ab, aba, abaab, abaaba\\}$", "$\\{a, b, abaab, abaaba\\}$", "$\\{a, ab, aba, abaaba\\}$"]
      },
      "q19_1": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Sets concatenation. Concatenating a set n times means concatenating every string in L with each string in $L$ n times",
        "question": "Let $\\Sigma$=$\\{a,b\\}$, $L$=$\\{ab,aba\\}$, What is $L^3$?",
        "answer": "$\\{ababab, abaabaab, abaabab, abaabaab, abababa, ababaaba, abaababa, abaabaaba\\}$",
        "choices": ["$\\{ababab, abaabaab, abaabab, abaabaab, abababa, ababaaba, abaababa, abaabaaba\\}$","$\\{ab, ababaab, abaabab, abaabaab, abababa, abaaba, abaababa, abaabaaba\\}$","$\\{ababab, baab, abaabab, abaaba, abab, ababaaba, abaababa, abaabaaba\\}$","$\\{ababab, ababa, abaabab, abaab, ababa, ababaaba, abaababa, abaabaaba\\}$","$\\{ababab, ababaab, abaabab, abaabaab, baba, ababaaba, abaaba, abaaba\\}$"]
      }
    }
  }
}
